KritiKalpa Saha

≤ saha.kritikalpa@gmail.com +91-8794761714

Frontend Developer

kriti-portfolio.vercel.app

in linkedin.com/in/kritikalpa-saha/

Enthusiastic and self-motivated frontend developer with 5+ years of experience in web application development. Worked in multicultural teams and adaptable to any situation. Eager to join your esteemed organisation and bring my skill in frontend development, and visual design to every project that will be received in the future.

Education

Higher Secondary(CBSE) | Assam Rifles Public School.

2016

B-Tech (Electrical) | National Institute of Technology Agartala.

2016-20

Skills

- Hands-on experience in Cross Platform Application Development.
- Experience in developing web based applications using MERN stack.
- Strong proficiency in languages like JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, C#, C++.
- Proficient in web technologies like HTML5, CSS3, React, Vue, NodeJS, ExpressJS, JSON, XML, REST, GraphQL etc.
- Experience with major global state management libraries like Vuex, Redux.
- Proficient in testing framework like Jest, Enzyme, RTL.
- Experienced in collaborative workspace environment. Experienced in Agile Techniques like SCRUM and KANBAN.
- Hands-on experience with databases like SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB etc.
- Worked on deploying and maintaining highly available workloads in most Major Cloud Providers like AWS, Google Cloud Service, Azure etc.
- Proficiency in debugging exercises and in Test Driven Development.
- Extensive work on UI/UX Design, Graphics Design and Product Design.
- Working knowledge of tools like Git, Jira, Notion, Clickup, Confluence, Figma, Photoshop etc.

Experience

SDE-1 | Frontend | MikeLegal | India

Dec, 2022 - Present

- Developed the Track Changes module for product "DocReview" that helps lawyers keep track of real-time changes in a contract.
- Leading the development of Mike Litigation tool frontend from scratch.
- Legacy code clean up, optimization and involved in debugging exercises.
- Code reviews and mentoring Junior developers and interns.

Frontend Lead | LongShot AI | Mumbai, India

Feb, 2022 - Jan, 2023

- Collaborated with the design team and revamped the entire app UI.
- Actively participated and pitched in design decisions and strategy meetings.
- Built LongShot chrome extension that featured as 2nd in Product of the Day at Product Hunt.
- · Collaborated with the Semrush team to integrate Semrush to LongShot

Senior Frontend Engineer | LongShot AI | India

Oct, 2021 - Jan, 2022

- Designed and developed new features. Maintenance and cleanup of existing code base. Worked with the support and QA team to debug the app.
- Developed the real-time collaboration feature in the app using WebRTC.

Frontend Engineer | Klinify | Singapore

May, 2021 - Oct, 2021

- Worked extensively on debugging and code cleanups to reduce existing code- debts.
- Collaborated with Designers, building advanced UI for the platform. Developed new independent features from scratch.
- Revamped the existing code review process and actively involved in strategy and design planning

Senior Analyst | React Developer | Capgemini | Mumbai, India

Sep, 2020 - Apr,2021

- Worked in multiple scalable projects, Inventory Management System(IMS) and Business Process tracker.
- Designed user requirement solutions from initial documentation to final specification.

Intern | Appato | Tripura, India

Dec, 2018 - May, 2019

- Developed user interface prototypes.
- Optimization of the existing code base and creating tests

FREELANCE WORK

Restaurant POS system and food menu | Hightree Cafe & Bistro | April, 2021

- Designed & developed both customer-facing and behind-the-desk application UI.
- Worked to sync the Order Management System with the restaurant Menu.

Web Application Development | Balaka Cinema | May, 2021

• Developed high fidelity Responsive Web Application for public viewers.

Projects

• Ena in Hogwarts | Android Game Development | May, 2020

Hobbies

Playing Chess, travelling, cooking and discussing new ideas with friends